# **Malav Vyas**

Ahmedabad, India malavvyas94@gmail.com

+91 9429632133

## **Summary**

Self-motivated IT professional seeking a technical position in which I can apply existing skills and continue to work with the latest technologies. With two years of professional experience in Information Technology, my expertise revolves around task automation, Exploit Development, Web/Desktop Application Development, and Penetration Testing. I have a strong knowledge of the latest Information Security practices and possess strong oral and written communication skills, as well as the ability to prioritize and multitask.

# **Experience**

Infovys Inc. - Nashik, India

October 2018 - Present

**Information Security Analyst** – Company's sole security analyst and developer, member of Security Engineering team. Responsibilities/accomplishments include but are not limited to:

- Antivirus administration
- Secure Coding
- •Security Auditing for Web/Android Applications as well as servers
- •Single-handedly designed and developed a multi-platform Antivirus System with Firewall
- •Miscellaneous Task automation in both Windows and Linux environments
- •Research and various side projects

E Cyber Fariyad, Adalaj Police - Adalaj, India

June 2018 - July 2019

**Cyber Crime Consultant** – Pro-Bono Cyber Crime Consultant for Adalaj Police Station.

Responsibilities include but are not limited to:

- •Educating Staff on analysis techniques, as well as scripting
- Proactively seeking and investigating suspicious activity of suspect

Girlscript Foundation- Nagpur, India

January 2017 – January 2018

**Core Team Member** – Senior member of the Operations team, responsible for supervising operations.

Responsibilities include but are not limited to:

- •Planning and Organizing Workshops, meetups for the Foundation
- •Conducting Information Technology related workshops as speaker
- •Maintaining Public Relations on behalf of the foundation

Commissioner of Police - Gurugram - Delhi, India

May 2017 - June 2017

**Cyber Crime Intern**—Got a Learning Experience of the Police Department's Cyber Crime Investigation. Individual responsibilities include but are not limited to:

- •Studied and analyzed various Cyber Crime Incidents.
- Worked with Forensic tools and equipments while following forensics investigation methodology
- •Developed and Presented a project on Web Application Attacks.

### Other Skills

- Proficient in C, C++, C#, Java, x86 Assembly language, Rust
- Linux/UNIX Administration
- •HTML/CSS/JavaScript/PHP
- Static code analysis (JavaScript, PHP, C#)
- •Scripting/Custom tool/program development (Bash, Python 2.7, PowerShell 2.0-4.0)
- Familiarity with various logging technologies/SIEMs (ELK Stack, Rsyslog, AlienVault, FireEye Helix)
- Docker Development
- Cloud Security (AWS)
- •Expert level network connectivity troubleshooting skills on all platforms of end user devices

#### **Education**

Most of the stuff is self taught. Thanks to Google, Stack Overflow, MSDN Library and various online forums.

# Graduation

•Information Technology Engineering, Gujarat Technological University

2020

## **Workshops and Sessions**

x86 Assembly - Preparing for the battle
 EggHunting - Exploit Development Techniques

IoT and Security

Exploit Development 101 ( 2 Days (20 Hour) Workshop)

Augmented Reality and Virtual Reality

Web Application Development

Cyber Awareness

Null Ahmedabad Null Ahmedabad Null Ahmedabad Null Ahmedabad Mozilla Foundation Mozilla Foundation

Infinite Defence Foundation

### **Projects**

- Exploit for GetGo Download manager Python
- Undetectable Keylogger Over WAN without static IP Python
- Fileless JavaScript Malware Dropper Javascript
- Barebone OS kernel with Graphics and keyboard support C and Assembly Language
- Remote Desktop Administration Tool ( platform Independent Java )
- Linux Command Shell C

### Research

- Pressing Importance of IoT Security Published Digital 4n6 Journal February 2020 Issue
  In this paper, I elucidate on misconfigurations in IoT devices and the possible impact on them as well as explain the pressing need for IoT security and my findings on them.
- Recruitment Based Resume Classification Ongoing
   In this research, we intend to make the process of hiring talents less tedious for employers by resume classification for recruitment.

#### Web Presence

- Secjuice Author <a href="https://www.secjuice.com/author/malav/">https://www.secjuice.com/author/malav/</a>
- Exploit-DB Author https://www.exploit-db.com/?author=10119
- Medium Author https://medium.com/@malavvyas98
- Packet Storm https://packetstormsecurity.com/files/author/14434/
- GeekFlux Author https://thegeekflux.in/authors/
- SecArmy Trainer <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Pe5qXbjuP">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Pe5qXbjuP</a> A
- Github <a href="https://github.com/malavvyas">https://github.com/malavvyas</a>
- Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/malav vyas1">https://twitter.com/malav vyas1</a>
- Personal Web Page <a href="https://malavvyas.github.io">https://malavvyas.github.io</a>

#### **Areas of Interest**

Cryptography, Malware Analysis, Linux Kernel and Networking, Exploit Development

References are available upon request.